A Guide to the The Papers of the Joseph Carrington Cabell Family ca. 1783-1887
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Correspondence of the Cabell and Related Families
  - Philip B. Cabell to his parents, Anne Blaws Cocke Cabell and Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1843-1852, 1859-1883, 2 folders, 186 items (Box 8)
  - Sally F. Cabell to her brother and sister-in-law, Philip and Julia Bolling Cabell 1850-1887, 45 items (Box 8)
  - Sally F. Cabell to her father, Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1861-1863, 17 items (Box 8)
  - William D. Cabell to his in-laws, Nathaniel Francis Cabell and Anne Blaws Cocke Cabell 1855-1865, n.d., 32 items (Box 8)
  - William D. Cabell to his brother-in-law, Philip B. Cabell 1865-1875, 31 items (Box 8)
  - Cary Charles Cocke to Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1833-1862, 29 items (Box 8)
  - John Hartwell Cocke to his son-in-law, Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1835-1861, 4 folders, 109 items (Box 9)
  - John Hartwell Cocke to his grandson, Philip B. Cabell 1843-1853, 44 items (Box 9)
  - John Hartwell Cocke, Jr. to Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1831-1835, 16 items (Box 9)
  - Louisa Cocke to Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1833-1840, 7 items (Box 9)
  - Lucy Oliver Cocke, wife of Dr. C.C. Cocke, to her sister-in-law, Anne Blaws Cocke Cabell 1840-1861, n.d., 3 folders, 152 items (Box 9)
  - Philip St. George Cocke to Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1834-1860, 31 items (Box 9)
  - The Reverend Richard De Charms (1796-1864) to Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1838-1860, n.d., 2 folders, 79 items (Box 9)
  - H.H. Hite to Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1865-1882, n.d., 19 items (Box 10)
  - Benjamin H. Magruder to Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1836-1838, 5 items (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to William Bolling: A-E 1840-1845 (Box 10)
    These include: [William Segar Archer?]; his daughter, M.L. Bolling; P.A. Bolling; his son, Thomas Bolling; Charles L. Botts; John M. Botts (circular letter); Frederick Boyden; General Alexander Brown; the Reverend John Cole; the Reverend N.H. Cobb (2 items); John H. Cocke (3 items); Deborah M. Couch (4 items); George P. Crump; Dr. [John?] Curd; Thomas Duke; R. Edmond; Charles Ellis; Thomas H. Ellis
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to William Bolling: F-H 1843-1845 (Box 10)
    These include: James Fenton; Alexander Garrett (2 items); Edward Gay (4 items); N.B. Gay; Charles Gennet (3 items); Dr. Harris; Lucy G. Harris; Mrs. H.C. Harrison; Martha Hoy; William H. Hubbard; Captain E.A. Huntley
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to William Bolling: J-P 1843-1844 (Box 10)
    These include: Ch. Johnson; Howel L. Kent; James Lyons; C.H. McCormick; the Reverend James McElroy; Heath Jones Miller; Nunnally Lawson; the Reverend Edward W. Peet; [Militia?] General [James W.] Pegram
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to William Bolling: R-S 1836-1845 (Box 10)
    These include: Charles Radziminski (3 items); R.B. Randolph; Richard Randolph; William B. Randolph; Richard Reins; Ann Rice; Wyndham Robertson (3 items); Anthony Robertson, Jr.; Mrs. Skipwith (invitation); Robert Skipwith; John C. Stratton
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to William Bolling: T-W 1842-1844 (Box 10)
    These include: [J.M.] Trevillian; Warwick & Barksdale; Joseph K. Weisiger (2 items); Whig Committee of Richmond; Mrs. Helen Wilmer (2 items); the Reverend J.P.B. Wilmer (3 items); the Reverend R.H. Wilmer
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to the Bolling Family 1823-1880, 7 items (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to Nathaniel Francis Cabell: A-B 1832-1871 (Box 10)
    These include: W.H.A.; the Reverend H. Alexander; Annie Arthur; C.Ashford; Dr. D.C. Barraud; Otway B. Barraud; John Roy Baylor; William M. Blackford; Professor Walter Blair (4 items); Colonel William Boulware; Robert L. Brown; John R. Bryan (2 items)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to Nathaniel Francis Cabell: C 1836-1883 (Box 10)
    These include: Alice Winston Cabell; C. Cabell; Fannie Grace Cabell (3 items); Dr. J.L. Cabell; J.L. Cabell; John Breckinridge Cabell; Julia Bolling Cabell (6 items); Mrs. Margaret C. Cabell; Mayo Cabell (3 items); Nannie Cabell (2 items); P.H. Cabell; P.C. Callaway; Judge John A. Campbell; Mrs. E.V. Carrington; Dr. William A. Carrington (5 items); John B. Cocke (2 items); W.R.C. Cocke; L.D. Crenshaw
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to Nathaniel Francis Cabell: E-H 1846-1873 (Box 10)
    These include: Augusta Edmonds (4 items); Robert Edmonds; Professor P.A. Emery; Thomas H. Farrar; Mrs. Alice Mosby Gardner, (1836-?) (2 items); John Harris; M.B. Harris; William B. Harrison; William H. Harrison (5 items); E.H. Hartsook; E.R. Hester (2 items); Isaac Irvine Hite; the Reverend Joseph Holdrich (4 items); Mrs. Alfred Hughes (2 items); John N. Humes (2 items); J.W. Leadenham (2 items); Daniel H. London (4 items); J.B. McClelland; M.L. McClelland; Thomas S. McClelland; Virginia P. Mosby (2 items); Lucie B. Palmer (2 items); B.E. Payne; James S. Penn; T. Benjamin Perkins; Joseph R. Putnam
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to Nathaniel Francis Cabell: L-P 1855-1887 (Box 10)
    They include: J.W. Leadenham (2 items), Daniel H. London (4 items), J.B.W. McClelland, Mrs. M.L. McClelland, Thomas S. McClelland, Mrs. Virginia P. Mosby (2 items), Lucie B. Palmer (2 items), B.E. Payne, James S. Penn, T.B.M. Perkins, Joseph R. Putnam
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to Nathaniel Francis Cabell: R-Y 1838-1885 (Box 10)
    These include: J.W. Randolph; C.C. Read (5 items); Evelyn C. Robinson (2 items); M.M. Robinson; Edmund Ruffin (2 items); Frank G. Ruffin; Nannie Russell; Minna Scott; Miles T. Shipman; Robert Skipwith; the Reverend B.M. Smith; N.M. Thomas; Samuel S. Thompson; Marion Tyree; Mrs. E.A. Upshur (2 items); R.L. Walker; the Reverend S.W. Watkins; H.N.B. Wood; Miss S.D. Woods; William H. Wyckoff (2 items); Charles Yancey (2 items)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to Philip B. Cabell and Julia Bolling Cabell 1844-1894, 16 items (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondents to the Cabell and related Families 1841-1896, 34 items (Box 10)
  - Ella Floyd Mosby (1846-?) to Nathaniel Francis Cabell (19 items) 1864-1881, 19 items (Box 10)
  - Isaac Read to his cousin, Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1824-1887, n.d., 38 items (Box 11)
  - Francis Nathaniel Watkins to Nathaniel Francis Cabell 1854-1885, 39 items (Box 11)
- Series III: Legal, Financial and Miscellaneous Papers
  - Legal and Financial Papers ca. 1832-1866, 10 items (Box 11)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Estate of Thomas Bolling 1816-1843, 25 items (Box 11)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - William Bolling 1783-1860, n.d., 3 folders, 211 items (Box 11)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - James River and Kanawha Company, including Correspondence of Joseph C. Cabell and William Bolling 1835-1845, 24 items (Box 11)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Estate of James Lownes 1818-1844, 30 items (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Estates of William Newburn, Sarah R. Newburn and William C.R. Newburn, with William Bolling Executor ca. 1817-1838, 4 folders, 141 items (Box 12)
  - Manuscripts and Notes by Nathaniel Francis Cabell ca. 1879, n.d., 9 items (Box 12)
  - News clippings 1825-1843, n.d., 49 items (Box 12)
  - News clippings re Professor George Bush 1844-1848, n.d., 33 items (Box 12)
  - Poetry Manuscripts n.d., 12 items (Box 12)
  - Report on the First Battle of Bull Run ca. 1861 Jul, (incomplete draft) (Box 12)
  - School Reports and Miscellaneous Papers, including notes by Philip B. Cabell about the resurrection of Jesus Christ 1862-1863, n.d., 11 items (Box 12)